

# Dexter Crago Software Engineer

My Personal Website

in LinkedIn (7) GitHub

dexter18crago@gmail.com

Hello! I'm Dexter, a full-stack software engineer with a strong grasp of programming fundamentals, lots of experience fixing my own code, and a strong drive to continue learning and improving my skills. Please feel free to check out my personal website ☑ to see some of my work and learn more about me and how I can start adding value to your team right away!

# Education

### **Software Engineering,** The Odin Project

Aug 2023 – May 2024

- Full stack web development program
- Created 20+ projects from scratch
- Programming & computer science fundamentals
- Testing with Jest and refactoring code
- Authentication, authorization, and API endpoints
- Using Git extensively and working with databases

### **Bachelor of Science,** Montana State University

Aug 2018 – May 2023

- Strong logical reasoning and analysis skills
- Communicating technical concepts to non-technical individuals
- Breaking down large problems into manageable pieces

# **Organizations**

# **Morning Star Elementary School,** *Tech Club Leader* Feb 2022 - May 2022

• Teaching elementary students math, science, technology, etc. concepts

# **Montana Indian Ministries,** *Summer Camp Leader* Jun 2015 – present

• Managing and teaching 50+ camp counselors

## Skills

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Git VCS, React.js, Jest, JSON, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, REST APIs, Passport.js, JWT

# Professional Experience

### Stevensville High School,

High School Science Teacher

Jan 2023 – Apr 2023

- Time management, organization, self-discipline
- Developing creative and engaging lesson plans
- Conducted, analyzed, and presented research

### Montana Club, Server

Jun 2015 - Mar 2021

- Increased sales from \$500 to \$1000/day in one year
- Developed new team workflows
- Trusted with closing out registers containing \$1000+
- Trained junior co-workers

### **City Life Community Center,** Youth Worker

Jun 2018 - Jun 2020

- · Working closely with a team to coordinate trips and events for 20+ students
- Adaptability, teachability, ability to work autonomously